As an experienced technical and security specialist, I am well versed in a range of aspects from low level technical processes such as automation, development, research, etc. To higher level concepts such as goal delivery, stakeholder communication and framework implementation (e.g., ISO 27001).

I believe I have demonstrated great value in all my previous employments. These have taken many forms such as automating tasks with either standard operating procedures or computational scripts/programs to increase company process efficiency, in some cases up to 10-fold. I have developed monitoring and practical applications when there were no solutions available in the market. However, I believe the biggest value that I can and have always provided, is my burning desire to learn, but also my own personal techniques and skills I have constructed over my career to perform this process as efficiently as possible.

In regard to my current career goals, we must look at the current global and economic situation. There's a lot of movement globally in the cyber world both good and bad. With recent humanitarian disasters and state sponsored attacks, I feel I have invaluable experience to bring to the table for any company in hardening their environments for both internal, stakeholder and customer needs.

Thank you very much for your time and consideration whilst reviewing my experience.

My up most pleasure,

Wayne Banner

Purriculum WAYNE BANNER



Glossop, Manchester, UK



07880 243370



Wayne.mbanner@gmail.com



> Technical Skills

Networking

Hardware

Programming

Security

Design



Manager Skills

Communication

Leadership

Teamwork

Motivational

Customer Satisfaction



Education

GCSE

Math: B Literacv: B English: B Chemistry: B Physics: B Geography: C ICT: Distinction

NVQ

Management & Business Enterprise: Lvl3 IT Professional: LvI3

Technical Qualifications

EC Council Certified Ethical Hacker (CEHv10) MCP (Microsoft Certified Professional) MCDST (Microsoft Certified Desktop Support Technician) Advanced Diploma for IT Professionals CompTia A+ CompTia Network+ Currently training towards CCNA + CCNA Security



Work Experience

Global Security Team

Chiesi Ltd, 333 Styal Rd, Wythenshawe, Manchester, M22 5LG November 2020 - Present

- Project managed 3 global security initiatives to over 20 international affiliates comprising of more than 6000 users and devices.
- Manage the implementation and maintenance of the global MFA policy, including but not restricted to onboarding of new affiliates, ensuring the continual application for new users and reporting to key C-level directors and stakeholders.
- Maintenance and development of vulnerability assessment process using the Nessus platform
- Consult and participate in global awareness and phishing campaigns.
- Help affiliates to implement controls and policies relating to security frameworks (ISO 27001/NoST/CyberEssentials/etc)
- Perform and or communicate with 3rd parties to remediate local security issues with our applications, servers, or infrastructure to maintain confidentiality, integrity, and availability.

UK IT Application, Infrastructure and Project Portfolio Manager

Chiesi Ltd, 333 Styal Rd, Wythenshawe, Manchester, M22 5LG May 2020 - Present

- Project manage to implement new applications and infrastructure or change management, providing continual support to the assets and employees.
- Developed bespoke applications to meet business needs that weren't available on the market.
- Implement processes and scripts to automate procedures such as asset states, asset management and reporting.
- Support the business and its end users with devices and the many local/cloud platforms.
- Consult with business stakeholders and departments from an information technology and security point of view.
- Liaise with 3rd parties for both IT and other departmental projects, providing technical expertise.



IT Infrastructure and Project Engineer

Amshire Solutions 4 Oak Green Stanley Green Business Park 2019-2020

- Take control of the full project process, from project creation to close out with customer satisfaction kept at the forefront the whole time. Plan, configure and install bespoke hardware implementations i.e., firewalls, switches, routers, WAPs, etc.
- Maintain professional and key communication with the customer and stakeholders throughout the process.
- Migrate many different types of servers over to new physical/virtual boxes including Exchange to the cloud (O365/Azure) using various methods depending on the situation i.e., cutover, import/export, swing.
- Build rapport and mutually beneficial relationships with customers and stakeholders during physical and virtual interactions.
- Work closely with the customer and stakeholders to implement custom application implementations to ease or automate processes within the company using python, Powershell, C#, C++, etc.
- Work closely and communicate with other project engineers to make sure any collaborative or handover work is performed smoothly, efficiently, and professionally, keeping strict records.

IT Network and Support Engineer

Amshire Solutions 4 Oak Green Stanley Green Business Park 2017 - 2019

- Designed and implemented automated backup reporting solution, reducing backup monitoring process time by 70%.
- Support and maintenance of multiple types of networks and servers.
- Extensive knowledge in Office 365 including exchange and Azure and cloud technology in general.
- Setup and configuration of various network devices.
 Routers/Switches/Firewalls etc. Specializing in Cisco devices.
- Created bespoke software for building multiple machines using the latest Powershell Framework which when implemented increases production above 900%
- Monitoring of server performance and implementing new network hardware to improve company performance and data confidentiality, integrity, and availability.

IT Infrastructure and Network Manager

CTUK Ltd, St Marks Lane Manchester 2013 – 2014

- Designing and implementation of new physical network as building was extended.
- Managing and maintenance of network and Active Directory.
- Maintain and continual support of e-commerce website.
- Train and manage staff on new software and implementation of business solutions.
- Created bespoke ordering software to migrate company to digital system.
- Monitoring of server performance and implementing new network hardware to improve company performance and data confidentiality, integrity, and availability.



Work Experience Cont.

Lv3 Advanced Apprenticeship (Management & Business Enterprise)

CTUK Ltd, St Marks Lane Manchester 2011 – 2012

First 6 months:

- Shadowing management (CEO), theory behind business and man management.
- Learning to communicate, motivate and delegate to staff and stakeholders.
- Building trust and relationship with current and potential customers.

Last 6 months:

- Planning and execution of solutions to business needs and possible problems.
- Project management and staff delegation to the project that was chosen for the course.
- Overseeing and reporting of project, training, and motivating staff and presenting progressions to stakeholders keeping to very keen timetables.



Personal Projects / Hobbies

Here you will find activities and projects that excite me outside of my professional life with a few examples of each

Capture the flags

- HackTheBox
- VulnHub
- My own personal devices (Wireless/physical devices, Kali, BashBunny, FlipperZero, etc)

Electronic development (Arduino, STM32, etc)

- Complete drone flight controller using a range of I2C and SPI sensors and STM32 bluepill as the brain
- Voice activated smart reptile vivarium with climate control and automated feeding
- Mazda RX8 to EV conversion implementing bespoke ECU (Arduino) and CANBUS control

Machine Learning

- Modelling social/financial relationships
- Modelling drone manoeuvre profiles using labelled data

Artificial Intelligence

- NearoEvolution of Augmented Topologies (Deep learning with evolutionary topology structures)
- Computer Vision for drone experiments
- FOREX/CRYPTO modelling using a mixture of known technical indicators and self-taught metas fused with sentiment analysis from social platforms
- OpenGym challenges